When everything went wrong, six men had the courage to do what was right.
13 Hours: The Secret Soldiers of Benghazi is a war,
action, history film directed by Michael Bay.
An American Ambassador is killed during an attack at a U.S.
compound in Libya as a security team struggles to make sense out of the chaos.
Jack Silva, played by John Krasinski.
Tyrone 'Rone' Woods, played by James Badge Dale.
John 'Tig' Tiegen, played by Dominic Fumusa.
Mark 'Oz' Geist, played by Max Martini.
Kris 'Tanto' Paronto, played by Pablo Schreiber.
Chris Stevens, played by Matt Letscher.
13 Hours: The Secret Soldiers of Benghazi is a 2016 American biographical
action-thriller film, directed and produced by Michael Bay.
Written by Chuck Hogan, it is based on the 2014 non-fiction book
13 Hours by American author Mitchell Zuckoff.
The film follows six members of the Annex Security Team who fought to defend the American diplomatic
compound in Benghazi, Libya after waves of attacks by militants on September 11, 2012.
The film stars James Badge Dale, John Krasinski, Pablo Schreiber, Max Martini, David Denman and
Dominic Fumusa, with supporting roles by Toby Stephens, Alexia Barlier and David Costabile.
Filming on location began on April 27, 2015, in Libya.
Upon its release on January 15, 2016, by Paramount Pictures, 13 Hours grossed over $69 million worldwide
against a production budget of $50 million, becoming one of Bay's lowest-grossing films.
It also received mixed reviews from critics, who praised its performances, action
sequences, and dark tone, but criticized the script for historical liberties.
Bay's direction also received a mixed response, with many criticizing his emphasis on
over-the-top action, but some also noting it as one of his most mature and grounded films.
13 Hours received an Oscar nomination for Best Sound
Mixing at the 89th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia),
based on novel or book, libya, assault rifle, grave.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.